<resources>
    <string name="app_name">30 Days of Running Tips</string>

    <string name="day_template">Day %1$d</string>

    <string name="tip_01_title">Become an Aerobic Monster</string>
    <string name="tip_01_description">
        Mileage isn’t everything, but most runners will become stronger aerobically by carefully
        and gradually increasing the volume of running they can handle. Increasing your mileage
        from year to year while still being able to hit your times in workouts and races will
        improve your VO2 max (ability to pump a lot of blood to working muscles), lactate threshold
        (ability to clear lactate and therefore not have to slow), and running economy (amount of
        oxygen needed to hold a certain pace).
    </string>

    <string name="tip_02_title">Practice Proprioception</string>
    <string name="tip_02_description">
        The simplest exercise is to close your eyes and stand on one foot. The proprioceptors in
        your feet will collaborate with your inner ear to help your brain know if you are swaying
        and determine what to do to keep yourself balanced. You’ll only be able to hold it for a
        few seconds at first but should be able to work up to 10 to 15 seconds at a time. Aim for a
        total of around a minute per leg during each session.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_03_title">Strengthen Your Whole Body</string>
    <string name="tip_03_description">
        Good runners condition their whole bodies. The arms drive the legs. Keep your upper body
        and core toned with a lot of push-ups, pull-ups, sit-ups, and back raises (don’t forget
        that the back is part of the core). Stay away from machine weights and stick to Pilates,
        climbing, and dynamic flexibility work like yoga.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_04_title">Run More Hills</string>
    <string name="tip_04_description">
        One of the beauties of hills is that they really work on dynamic power, hip strength, and
        hip mobility because you need to be able to go and drive those hips really high to get up.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_05_title">Quit Trying to Set Your PR</string>
    <string name="tip_05_description">
        Be process-oriented, not outcome-oriented. Get a little better with each training session —
        a stronger squat, a harder effort on intervals. Don’t obsess about race day.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_06_title">Hydrate (Especially Before Trail Races)</string>
    <string name="tip_06_description">
        Due to their remote locations, many trail races have few (if any) water stations. Make sure
        to hydrate for days in advance, and — depending on the distance of the race — consider
        carrying a water bottle or hydration pack during the event.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_07_title">Cultivate Controlled Consistency</string>
    <string name="tip_07_description">
        “I try not to run 100 percent. I perform 80 percent on Tuesday, Thursday, and Saturday and
        then at 50 percent Monday, Wednesday, Friday, and Sunday,” says Eliud Kipchoge.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_08_title">Stretch and Refuel Immediately Post-Race</string>
    <string name="tip_08_description">
        There’s a natural temptation when you finish a race to collapse on the ground and bask in
        your own private glory. This is a bad idea.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_09_title">Find a Routine, Then Stick to It</string>
    <string name="tip_09_description">
        I dialed in my race-day outfit and nutrition plan in advance to eliminate any surprises.
        I slept more, stopped drinking alcohol, and ate my vegetables. I put on the same clothes
        I had been training in for the past three weeks—black shorts, white top, gray socks—and ate
        my pre-planned breakfast of one banana, half a Clif Bar, and half a cup of coffee.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_10_title">Don’t Freak Out if You’re Undertrained</string>
    <string name="tip_10_description">
        A lot of people ruminate and freak out. Then they have all this nervous energy and are
        toast during the race. The key is to stay calm and not expend energy worrying about the race.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_11_title">Fix Your Stride</string>
    <string name="tip_11_description">
        He had to change everything about his stride — from the way his feet were hitting the ground
        to the way he swung his arms as he ran. It was a difficult adjustment, but he had the
        benefit of knowing he’d already tried virtually everything else.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_12_title">Eat Whole Foods</string>
    <string name="tip_12_description">
        Try to eat whole foods that look as close to how they are grown as possible. Avoid the
        processed food — like foods that dominate most conventional grocery chains. They’re packed
        with sodium, sugar, and empty calories and are a drain on your digestive system.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_13_title">Slow Down to Spare Carbs</string>
    <string name="tip_13_description">
        She ran smart, at a pace that felt sustainable. She estimates she could have run a single
        hard marathon in about 3 hours 30 minutes at the time—over 50 minutes faster than her
        average over the ten marathons. Her marathon pace was slow, so she had little need for
        fast energy from carbohydrates.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_14_title">It’s Not All About the Carbs</string>
    <string name="tip_14_description">
        Runners whose number one goal is to lose weight can cut the pasta, bread, and cereals and
        have enough energy to complete many of the easy runs in 30 to 60 minutes. Most healthy
        diets will still provide enough incidental carbs—byproducts of fruit and beans—to fuel you.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_15_title">Random Massages Are a Bad Idea</string>
    <string name="tip_15_description">
        Every athlete’s body responds differently to massage; you don’t want to find out the week
        before your race that deep tissue work makes you uncomfortably sore.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_16_title">Layer Up When It’s Cold</string>
    <string name="tip_16_description">
        It’s easy to see the weather and darkness as a reason not to work out. The price tag might
        sting up front, but buying clothes like a moisture-wicking base layer, gloves, and a
        breathable wind-blocking top will make training outside a lot more enjoyable.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_17_title">You Need to Sprint More</string>
    <string name="tip_17_description">
        Five percent of an athlete’s total weekly mileage should be taken up by sprints. Someone
        running 30 miles a week should run hill sprints for 1.5 of those miles. It’s similar in
        theory and practice to speedwork on a track.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_18_title">Get a Hydration Pack (Especially for Ultras)</string>
    <string name="tip_18_description">
        Yes, there will be aid stations. But there’s no telling how much time will pass between
        them, so bring your own fluids in a handheld bottle, pack, or belt. Which one you choose
        is a matter of preference.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_19_title">Patience Is a Virtue</string>
    <string name="tip_19_description">
        In distance running, you’ve got to learn to love the process. Whether it’s in training
        (it takes a lot of time to get better) or in racing (holding back for the first 20 miles
        of a marathon), patience is a virtue. There are no quick fixes. It’s about believing in
        the plan and executing.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_20_title">Don’t Hydrate Too Much Right Before Running</string>
    <string name="tip_20_description">
        Sloshing in your stomach is a sign that water has not worked its way into your bloodstream,
        providing a full feeling that’s a ruse for hydration.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_21_title">Take Recovery Days Seriously</string>
    <string name="tip_21_description">
        The day after a tough workout, the most you want to do is jog lightly or do some form of
        cross-training, like cycling. You need a recovery day after a hard day. No exceptions.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_22_title">Make It Social</string>
    <string name="tip_22_description">
        Get a group together, or join a local running club. When you’re socially and emotionally
        invested in your workouts, it’ll be harder for you to skip them. Having running buddies
        will help keep you from burning out or slacking off.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_23_title">Don’t Pick Just One Running Partner</string>
    <string name="tip_23_description">
        One of the most basic ways to add a little variety to your running life is finding
        different running partners. You don’t need to be monogamous about whom you run with. The
        same principle applies for those who always run alone: Try joining a group for long weekend
        runs and (re)discover the joys of exercising with your fellow homo sapiens.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_24_title">Get Off Your Feet Before a Race</string>
    <string name="tip_24_description">
        Take it easy the day and night prior to race day. Race organizers don’t make that easy by
        scheduling interesting expos and panel discussions the day before, where you are on your
        feet, walking around, expending energy. Discipline yourself to keep that to a minimum,
        making a conscious effort to sit and rest with your feet up as much as possible. Don’t
        squander the good work you’ve done during your taper in the last day or two.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_25_title">Visualize Success</string>
    <string name="tip_25_description">
        Begin by taping an audio narrative for yourself that recreates, in as much sensual detail
        as possible, the sensation of performing your sport. Take careful notes the next time you
        practice…and work those into the script. Then narrate the tape entirely in the first
        person, present tense… and choose crucial moments.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_26_title">Use Technology (But Not Too Much)</string>
    <string name="tip_26_description">
        Apps from MapMyRun and the USATF can help you plot your training routes in less time (no
        more driving them beforehand). For trail running, figure out how long it takes you to run
        a mile — maybe two minutes longer than on roads — and go by time instead. Garmin GPS
        watches track your distance and pace. But don’t let your tools get in the way.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_27_title">Maybe Skip the Long Run</string>
    <string name="tip_27_description">
        You can’t just look at a singular long run or back-to-back long runs. You have to look at
        the whole picture. Every run is like bricks that add up over time.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_28_title">Know When Your Running Shoes Are Worn Out</string>
    <string name="tip_28_description">
        The typical lifespan of a shoe is between 300 and 600 miles. Shoes will start to feel a
        little different after about 200 miles — it’s a depreciation curve. Each company has a
        different point at which their shoes will feel really flat, but it’s important to know that
        shoes do have a lifespan. It might not be immediately clear when your shoes have bitten the
        dust, but there are a few indications that it’s time to invest in a new pair.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_29_title">Do Not Run Drunk</string>
    <string name="tip_29_description">
        For one, alcohol’s a poison. Two, while it can increase aggression (a positive, depending
        on the sport), it can also adversely affect coordination, planning, and execution of
        movement. And three, it’s a powerful diuretic, so it depletes your water volume, much of
        which your body takes from your blood plasma.
    </string>

    <string name="tip_30_title">Don’t Run Injured</string>
    <string name="tip_30_description">
        It’s hard to sit it out while waiting for an injury to heal. You risk setting back training
        and racing goals, not to mention losing a sweet endorphin rush. But whatever ails you will
        take longer to heal — or get worse — if you run through the pain.
    </string>
</resources>